Inventory of the Armistead-Cocke Papers 1680-1907
Earl Gregg Swem Library, College of William and Mary
- Letters, accounts and papers of the Armistead-Cocke family, 1756-1844. (Box 1-4)
  - Bowler Cocke, Bremo to brother, William Cocke, Cumberland, February 22, 1791., ALS. (Box-folder 2:65)
    Sent corn. Hired a new overseer, Smith. Sale of wheat. The trial of a Negro.
  - James Brown, Richmond to William Cocke, April 12, 1791., MS. S. (Box-folder 2:66)
    Accounts, from November 1790 to date, for salt, iron, wheat, leather, waggonage of tobacco, pork and draft on Donald and Burton.
  - William Cocke, Cumberland County to Alexander Moore, King William Co, April 20, 1791., D. S. (Box-folder 2:67)
    Agreement that Moore will cultivate land for 5 years and then become the owner.
  - Price and Owen to Mrs. Elizabeth Adams, June 23, 1791., MS. (Box-folder 2:68)
    Accounting of money.
  - Joseph Weaver to William Cocke, Cumberland, July 14, 1791., MS. S. H. (Box-folder 2:69)
    Bill for carrying tobacco of Mrs. Adams to the canal.
  - Joseph Weaver, Amherst to ?, July 14, 1791., ALS. (Box-folder 2:70)
    William Creacy (or Cresey) took too large and order of money on Weaver.
  - Jno. and Thomas Gilliat, Richmond to William Cocke, July 20, 1791., MS. (Box-folder 2:71)
    Account for women's clothing. On reverse, account of items furnished Mrs. Maria Armistead and for tuition for Charles Carter Armistead.
  - Elizabeth Adams to William Cocke, Cumberland, August 21, 1791., ALS. (Box-folder 2:72)
    Exchange of servants. Harry's death.
  - William Cocke, Cumberland County to ?, Buckingham Co, November 23, 1791., D.S. Fragments. (Box-folder 2:73)
    Agreement for building a house, "with a plain Cornice."
  - Joseph Fauntleroy to William Cocke, Cumberland Co, 1792., ALS. (Box-folder 2:74)
    Death of Mrs Elizabeth Adams, settlement of part of the estate between her daughter Sally Sarah and William Cocke [her son].
  - J. Woodville to Mrs. Maria Armistead, 1792?., ALS. (Box-folder 2:75)
    Schooling of her son Charles Carter Armistead.
  - William A. Fry to William Cocke, February 1, 1792., MS. S. (Box-folder 2:76)
    Account for money lent.
  - William A. Fry to William Cocke, Cumberland County, March 23, 1792., DS. (Box-folder 2:77)
    Agreement to rent Negroes and plantation on Rockfish River, Amherst County, part of estate of Thomas Adams, deceased.
  - Thomas Massie, Frederick, [husband of Sarah Cocke, sister of William], to [William Cocke], May 1792., ALS. (Box-folder 2:78)
    Family accounts and death of [William]'s mother [Mrs. Elizabeth Fauntleroy Cocke Adams].
  - Donald & Burton, London, to William Cocke, Cumberland County, [Virginia], May 12, 1792., ALS. (Box-folder 2:79)
    Sends account.
  - Joseph Weaver to William Cocke, Cumberland County, [Virginia], May 30, 1792., ALS. (Box-folder 2:80)
    Sale of slaves and horses. Crops.
  - Bowler Cocke, Bremo, [Fluvanna County, Virginia] to [William Cocke], brother, May 31, 1792., ALS. (Box-folder 2:81)
    His fall from a horse.
  - Letter, June 3, 1792., Ms. (Box-folder 2:82)
    Repaying William Cocke for building a bridge across Knockbuckle Stream, by wheat growers.
  - Frances Deane & County, Cartersville, [Virginia] to W[illia]m Cocke, October 3-November 6., 14 items. Ms. (Box-folder 2:83)
    Wheat receipts.
  - Robert Burton, for Donald & Burton, London, to William Cocke, Decem[ber] 31, 1792., Ms. S. (Box-folder 2:84)
    Account of sale of tobacco and settlement of bonds.
  - Peter Kemp, Jur., Urbanna to William Cocke, Cumberland [County, Virginia], Jan[uar]y 16, 1793., ALS. (Box-folder 2:85)
    Shipment of tobacco from Tappahannock.
  - Ann C[leves] Armistead, Hesse to Mrs. Jane Cocke [sister-in-law], Cumberland [County], Feb[ruary] 6, 1793., ALS. (Box-folder 2:86)
    Clothes and family news.
  - Ann C[leves] Armistead to [mother] Maria Armistead, March 11, 1793., D.S. (Box-folder 2:87)
    Sale of Negro living at house of Thomas Taylor Byrd [husband of Mary, dau. of William Armistead], Frederick.
  - W. Anderson & County, London, to William Cocke, Cumberland County, Virginia, March 13, 1793., LS. (Box-folder 2:88)
    Money due on a draft.
  - M[aria] A[rmistead], Hesse, to Jane [Cocke, her daughter, wife of William], April 26, 1793., ALS. (Box-folder 2:89)
    Family matters. Marriage of daughter Nancy [Ann Cleves] to Mr. [John P.] Pleasants.
  - James Tho[ma]s & Fran[ci]s Deane, Cartersville [Virginia] to William Cocke, Cumberland, Nov[ember] 9, 1793., ALS. (Box-folder 2:90)
    Account.
  - John Warden, Richmond to [Maria Armistead], Dec[embe]r 4, 1793., ALS. (Folder 2:91)
    Case of Powell v. Armistead's Executors, concerning William Armistead's will.
  - W[illia]m Nelson to [Maria Armistead], Jan[uar]y 29, 1794., ALS. (Box-folder 2:92)
    Case of Powell v. [Armistead's] Executors. Mr. [John] Warden is an able friend. Consulted Tho[ma]s Tabb.
  - Maria Armistead, Hesse, to [daughter] Mrs. Jane Cocke, Cumberland [County, Virginia], August 2, 1794., ALS. (Box-folder 2:93)
    Death of Godfrey; consolation. Illness in the family.
  - Sarah Daingerfield to Mrs. Maria Armistead, Hesse, December 24, 1794., ALS. (Box-folder 2:94)
    Sarah Daingerfield to Mrs. Maria Armistead, Hesse. Health, the phaeton and chocolate.
  - John & Thomas Gilliat, Richmond [Virginia], Dec[ember] 12, 17[95?]., Ms. (Box-folder 2:95)
  - W[illia]m Nelson, Richmond, [Virginia] to [William] Cocke, Cumberland County [Virginia], March 8, 1796., ALS. (Box-folder 2:96)
    Death of Mrs. [Maria] Armistead. Her papers in the [Powell v. Armistead] lawsuit.
  - Eleanor Armistead, Richmond, [the cottage] to Mrs. Jane Cocke, Cumberland [County, Virginia], May 26, 1797., ALS. (Box-folder 2:97)
    Family reunion. Marriage of Mrs. Randolph. The coming marriage of her brother Phil to Miss Betsy Page.
  - Ch[arle]s C[arter] Armistead, Baltimore [Maryland] to [brother-in-law] William Cocke, Sept[ember] 21, 1797., ALS. (Box-folder 2:98)
    Family news. The Hesse estate.
  - W[illia]m Nelson, Caroline [County, Virginia] to William Cocke, Cumberland County, Feb[ruary] 20, 1798. (Box-folder 2:99)
    Leasing Hesse house to Mr. Van Bibber and the house's burning down. Living in Matthews County
  - Price, King William County [Virginia] to William Curtis, Gloucester County [Virginia], 18[?]., D. Dr. (Box-folder 2:100)
    Deed for property in Gloucester County on Piankatank River.
  - Lewis M. Rivalain, Richmond [Virginia] to William Cocke, Cumberland C[ount]y Virginia, August 6, 1803., ALS. (Box-folder 2:101)
    Arranging insurance for insurance for Cocke's barn.
  - Rob[er]t H. Byrd, Clementtown Mills to William Cocke, Oakland, Cumberland [County, Virginia] April 27, 1807., ALS. (Box-folder 2:102)
    Flour business.
  - Alban Gilpin for Gilpin, Cocke & County to William Cocke, Cumberland, [Virginia], Nov[embe]r 23, 1807., ALS. (Box-folder 2:103)
    Settlement of account.
  - Sam[ue]l Parsons & Son to William Cocke, 12th month, 11, 1807., Ms. S. (Box-folder 2:104)
    Receipt for flour.
  - Edm[und] Randolph, Richmond to John Hollins, Baltimore, July 18, 1808., ALS. Encl. (Box-folder 2:105)
    Bishop [James] Madison's draft on Hollins, for his son, [Peyton Randolph].
  - The Spirit of Seventy-Six, Richmond, April 11, 1809., N. (Box-folder 2:106)
  - William Cocke, Cumberland County, [Virginia] to Daniel Ashton, Louisa County, [Virginia], August 1, 1811., DS. (Box-folder 2:107)
    Agreement that Ashton will be an apprentice miller.
  - [William Cocke], Dec. 20, 1811-Jan[uar]y 7, 1813., Ms. (Box-folder 2:108)
    Account sheet.
  - William Cocke, Cumberland County [Virginia] to William Powers, Cumberland County, [Virginia], November 20, 1812., D. (Box-folder 2:109)
    Agreement to hire Powers as overseer.
  - William A. Cocke, Williamsburg [Virginia] to William Cocke [father] near Cartersville, May 20, 1817., ALS. (Box-folder 2:110)
    Hessian fly affecting the wheat. His cousin, John Coles, has nervous fever. Asks for money.
  - Ferd[i]n[an]d S. Campbell, William and Mary College to William Cocke, Cartersville [Virginia], July 6, 1818., Ms. P.S. (Box-folder 2:111)
    Report on son William [A. Cocke] in Chemical and Moral classes.
  - Harrison [?] Hall to W[illia]m Cocke, Cartersville [Virginia], 1819., LS. (Box-folder 2:112)
    Portfolio subscription. Requests news of Mr. R. H. Atkinson.
  - William Armistead, Culpeper County, [Virginia] to William Cocke, Cartersville [Virginia], August 7, 1819., ALS. (Box-folder 2:113)
    Drought. Acquiring Burnett seeds for Peter Bowdoin of Hungais, Northampton County, [Virginia] and Genl. Nathaniel Carzell of Sussex County, [Virginia].
  - Eliza J. Carrington, Richmond [Virginia] to William Cocke, June 21, 1820-June 27, 1821., Ms.S. (Box-folder 2:114)
    2 receipts for payment on a debt.
  - William Cocke to Robert Taylo, April 23, 1821., Ms. S.R. (Box-folder 2:115)
    Promissory note.
  - Benjamin P. Johnson, C[arters]ville [Virginia] to William Cocke, Cumberland [County, Virginia], May 5, 1822., ALS. (Box-folder 2:116)
    Treatment of a Negro girl.
  - M[aria] C. B[yrd] to [cousin] William A. Cocke, Cartersville [Virginia], February 27, 1823., ALS. (Box-folder 2:117)
    Travelling. Family news. Character of Napoleon.
  - Eliza J. Carrington, Richmond [Virginia] to William Cocke, July 6, 1824., Ms. S. (Box-folder 2:118)
    Receipt for interest paid on a bond.
  - Will of William Cocke, Cumberland County, [Virginia], March 20, 1828., DS. (Box-folder 2:119)
    Partitions land and describes how he wishes to be buried.
  - [Miss Buruss, sister to addressee], [Washington, Adams County, Miss. and Mary H. Burruss [mother of addressee] to Mrs. Elizabeth Curtis, Gloucester C[our]t House, July 3, 1826., ALS. (Box-folder 3:1)
    The E.F. Academy, Eternity and God. Father appointed to Port Gibson.
  - I[sabella] S. Burwell, Carter Hall to [sister] Harriet P. Dixon, Airville, near Gloucester Ct. House, July 4, 1826., ALS. (Box-folder 3:2)
    Family news. Hot Spring resorts.
  - [?] Mexico, to Warner T. Jones, Gloucester County, Court House, Sept[ember] 28, 1827., ALS. (Box-folder 3:3)
    Promotion. Departure from Camp Bejara. Genl. Cushing coming to visit. Friends in Santa Anna are Bob Hughes, Major Kenly, Dr. Tilghman and Dr. Field.
  - Franklin Dabney, Gloucester to Miss Harriet P. Dixon, Millwood September 8, [1835?]., ALS. (Box-folder 2:4)
    Love letter. Hopes she rejects the suit of Mr. Nelson.
  - [Ann P. Jones?] [Lowland Cottage] to Cousin, Miss Harriet P. Dixon, Milwood, Frederick County, [Virginia], Nov[ember] 20, [1835?]., AL. (Box-folder 3:6)
    Preaching at the Poplars and at Mr. Taliaferro's. Dined at Airville.
  - B. Witt, Sandy River to William A. Cocke, Cartersville [Virginia], Jan[uar]y 9, 1836., ALS. (Box-folder 3:7)
    [Marriage?] Witt's injuries.
  - J[acob] C. Sheldon, Executor of John L. Dixon, January 1, 1836-Nov[ember] 26, 1838., Ms. (Box-folder 3:8)
    Account for money paid and received.
  - Martha Jones, Lowland cottage to [daughter] Miss Harriet T. Jones, Loutto Post Office, Feb[ruary] 15, [1836?]., ALS. (Box-folder 3:9)
    Illness, and death of Mrs. Smith and Mrs. Snow. Their school, composed of Mann Jones, John Dixon, and John and William Fox. Cousin Francis Tomkies is coming to Gloucester.
  - [Mrs. Edmonia Randolph Preston], Lexington [Virginia] to [her daughter] Mrs. Elizabeth R. Cocke, Cartersville [Virginia][wife of William A. Cocke], June 4, 1839., AL. (Box-folder 3:10)
    Family news and weather. Farming.
  - Here[?] [Harriet T. Curtis?], Belleville to Mrs. H[arriet P.] Sheldon, Williamsburg, [ca. 1840]., L. (Box-folder 3:11)
    Minister Cole Hodges and Mr. Rodher. Sending a package for the Judge.
  - Fetter & Londsdale, New Orleans [La.] to William A. Cocke, Cartersville [Virginia], June 23, 1841., ALS. (Box-folder 3:12)
    Tobacco shipping. On second sheet, printed list of merchandise and marketing information.
  - Ch[arles] C[hicester] Curtis and P.E. Tabb, November 15, 1844., Ms. S. (Box-folder 3:13)
    Certificate that account of Richard P. Jones, written by W[illia]m H. Allmand, is correct.
  - W.H. Allmand, U.S.S. Jamestown, Cape de Verdes to Charles C. curtis, Wareham, Gloucester Ct. House [Virginia], August 29, 1845., ALS. (Box-folder 3:14)
    Settlement of a suit. His cruise to Madiera and the Canary Islands.
  - Ch[arles] Cocke, Esmont to Dr. J.D. Shelton or Dr. Nicholas Warren, Oct[tober] 21, [18]45., ALS. (Box-folder 3:15)
    Requests medical attention for his man Jonah.
  - Newspaper accounts of Gov. Thomas of Maryland lawsuit, 1847., Cl. (Box-folder 3:16)
    Papers connected with the suit of Gov. Thomas of Maryland and his unfortunate wife Sally McDowell.[A Genl. Jones was counsel for Thomas.]
  - C[harles] C[hichester] Curtis, Chillicothe, [Ohio] to [wife] Mrs. H[arriet] T. Curtis, Gloucester Co[urt] House, June 10 [18]47., ALS. (Box-folder 3:17)
  - C[harles] C[hichester] Curtis, Chillicothe, [Ohio] to Mrs. H[arriet] T. Curtis [his wife], Gloucester C[ourt] House [Virginia], July 7, [18]47., ALS. (Box-folder 3:18)
    Sale of property in Highland and Adams counties. Traveling.
  - C[harles C[hicester] Curtis, Baltimore [Maryland] to [wife] Mrs. H[arriet] T. Curtis, Wareham, Gloucester [County, Virginia], Sept[ember] 27, 1847., ALS. (Box-folder 3:19)
    Sends supplies. Wheat shipment.
  - C[harles] C[hicester] Curtis, Nov[embe]r 1847., Ms. Incomplete. (Box-folder 3:20)
    "Horses bought in Ohio.. ."
  - William A. Cocke, [Cartersville, Virginia] to [?], March 16, [1848?]., ALS. (Box-folder 3:21)
    Tobaco sales. "I hear the distant thunder rumbling in our own beloved country." quoted Virgil on the war in Europe.
  - Valeou [?] Pasteur, Washington to Dr. Major [?], March 28, 1848., ALS. (Box-folder 3:22)
    "Sale of Forkes Plantation," planned with Rush Floyd.
  - C[harles] Le Baron, Mobile [Alabama] to Richard P. Jones, Gloucester County [Virginia], April 1, 1851., ALS. Cl. (Box-folder 3:23)
    C[harles] Le Baron, Mobile [Alabama] to Richard P. Jones, Gloucester County [Virginia] [brother of Harriet who married Charles Curtis and their daughter married Charles Curtis and their daughter married Thomas L.P. Cocke.] Settlement of estate of Mr. [George L.] Fauntleroy.
  - W[arner] T. Taliaferro, Belleville, Gloucester County [Virginia] to Dormes Oakes, Middlesex County [Virginia], Dec[ember] 28, 1851., ALS. (Box-folder 3:24)
    Miss Booth. As Dr. Booth had few debts, the sale of a slave should settle the account for his own services.
  - W. & G. Gwathmey, Richmond [Virginia] to W[illia]m A. Cocke, Cartersville [Virginia], April 22, 1853., ALS. (Box-folder 3:25)
    Sale of tobacco.
  - [Miss?] E.S. Booth to Cousin, Nov[ember] 26, [18]55., ALS. (Box-folder 3:26)
    Settlement of [estate of Dr. Booth]. Money is to be left wtih Mr. Curtis if she is not at Wareham.
  - H[arriet] P. Sheldon, Williamsburg [Virginia] to Maria [Curtis] Jones [cousin-in-law], March 23, 1857., ALS. (Box-folder 3:27)
    Troubles sent by God, especially the death of Mr. Langhorn. Mr. [Jacob C.] Sheldon is sick. Family news.
  - W[illia]m H. Dindas, Post Office Dept. to Mr. R.H. Garnett, Lloyds, Essex County, [Virginia], March 31, 1857., ALS. (Box-folder 3:28)
    Contract made with R.F. Northern for carrying mail.
  - John L. Manning, Warner Hall [Gloucester County] to Col. Warner T. Jones, 21 Reg. Virginia Militia, Oct[obe]r 18, 1859., ALS. (Box-folder 3:29)
    Projected celebration at Yorktown. Patriotism. Preservation of the Republic.
  - Henry Dent, Louisville [Kentucky] to Madame [?], August 15, 1830., ALS. (Box-folder 3:30)
    Payment on a mortgage assumed from T.L. Phillips.
  - Army of the Confederate States of America form, 186[?]., Ms. P. (Box-folder 3:31)
    Form for monthly return of the captain.
  - Jno. T. Hibble, Tappahonic to Col. [Warner T.] Jones, Jan[uary] 22, [18]61., ALS. (Box-folder 3:32)
    Upon Genl. Taliaferro's orders, collected guns in the county. Guns of Col. Hayes and Col. Taylor. Completion of arsenal. Asks for job on Taliaferro's staff.
  - W[illiam] F[auntleroy] Cocke to brother [Thomas L.P. Cocke, Cartersville [Virginia], [June 1861]. (Box-folder 3:33)
    Family news and agriculture. Formation of a company in Cumberland.
  - W[illiam] F[auntleroy] C[ocke], Manassas' Station to mother [Elizabeth Randolph Preston Cocke, Cartersville, Virginia], June 17, 1861., ALS. (Box-folder 3:34)
    Edmund [R. Cocke, writer's brother] sent news about obstructing roads and fords. Promotion of officers. Cousin Robert Preston. War maneuvers.
  - W[illiam] F[auntleroy] C[ocke], Fairfax to mother [Elizabeth Randolph Preston Cocke, Cartersville, Virginia] July 9, 1861., ALS. (Box-folder 3:35)
    Movement toward Alexandria. Expects an attack. Thomas [L.P. Cocke] is needed at home. "Most officers, as they make more money by their offices than they did by their professions or trades get less credit for patriotism." Agriculture.
  - T[homas] L.P. Cocke, Richmond [Virginia] to Mrs. E[lizabeth] R[andolph] Cocke, Cartersville [Virginia], July 19 [1861]., ALS. (Box-folder 3:36)
    Fight at Manassas. Cally Heath came down.
  - [William Fauntleroy Cocke], Camp near Centreville, [Virginia] to Tom [Thomas L.P. Cocke], August 7, 1861., L. (Box-folder 3:37)
    Family news. His description of Battle of Bull Run.
  - W[illiam] F[auntleroy] C[ocke], Centreville, [Virginia] to mother [Elizabeth Randolph Preston Cocke], Cartersville, [Virginia], Jan[uary] 4, [1862]., ALSC. (Box-folder 3:38)
    Politics of the artillery company. Behavior of Pendleton. Clothing.
  - W[illiam] F[auntleroy] C[ocke], Centreville, [Virginia] to mother [Elizabeth Randolph Preston Cocke], Cartersville, [Virginia], Jan[uary] 17, [1862]., ALSC. (Box-folder 3:39)
    The members of his mess. Food is of fine quality. Family news.
  - W[illia]m F[auntleroy] Cocke to Mrs. E[lizabeth] R[andolph] Cocke, Cartersville [Virginia], Feb[ruary] 5, 1862., C. (Box-folder 3:40)
  - W[illiam] F[auntleroy] C[ocke], Yortown [Virginia] to mother, [Elizabeth Randolph Preston Cocke, Cartersville [Virginia], April 25, 1862., ALS. (Box-folder 3:41)
    Troop movements. Housing. Family news.
  - T[homas] L.P. C[ocke] to [Elizabeth Randolph Preston Cocke], Oakland, May 4, 1862., ALS. (Box-folder 3:42)
    Troop movements near Winchester and Harrisonburg. Uncle [J.T.L.] Preston is well.
  - T[homas] L.P. C[ocke], Dover Dam Station [Fort Donaldson] to mother [Elizabeth Randolph Preston Cocke], Oakland, June 24 [1862]., ALS. (Box-folder 3:43)
    Flanking McClellan's force. News of his brothers.
  - T[homas] L.P. C[ocke], Dover Dam Station [Fort Donaldson] to mother [Elizabeth Randolph Preston Cocke], Oakland, June 24 [1862]., ALS. (Box-folder 3:43)
  - T[homas] L.P. C[ocke], Whiteoak Swamp, [Virginia] to mother [Elizabeth Randolph Preston Cocke], July 3, [18]62., ALS. (Box-folder 3:44)
    Edmund [R. Cocke] was well after the recent battle.
  - Edmund R. C[ocke], Camp near Richmond and [William Fauntleroy Cocke] to mother [Elizabeth Randolph Preston Cocke], Aug[ust] 8 [1862]., ALS. (Box-folder 3:45)
    Hot weather. Cousin Charles Moncure. Edmund leads a relaxed life.
  - Edmund R. Cocke, Camp near Guinea [Guney Station?] to mother [Elizabeth Randolph Preston Cocke], Jan[uar]y 26, 1863., ALS. (Box-folder 3:46)
    Philadelphia press reports movements of Yankee forces inaccurately. Will fall back to Richmond before fighting. Tom [L.P. Cocke]'s company is near Port Royal. Furloughs.
  - W[illiam] F[auntleroy] C[ocke], Camp near Guinea [Guiney Station?] to mother [Elizabeth Randolph Preston Cocke], Jan[uary] 30, [18]63., ALS. (Box-folder 2:47)
    Their man Abner. Troop movements in the rain. Vaccinations. Shoes and clothing. Wheat.
  - W[illiam] Fauntleroy] Cocke], Camp near Guinea [Guiney Station?] to mother [Elizabeth Randolph Preston Cocke], Feb[ruary] 11, [18]63., ALS. (Box-folder 3:48)
    Work on breastworks. Furlough of Dr. Weymouth.
  - T[homas] L.P. C[ocke], Gen[eral] Hos[ital], Richmond, to mother [[Elizabeth Randolph Preston Cocke], Feb[ruary] 12 [18]63., ALS. (Box-folder 3:)
    Attempts to get a discharge from a hospital. Getting a substitute.
  - [?], Richmond [Virginia] to [?] [Gloucester County, Virginia], April 8, 1863., L. [last page or so missing]. (Box-folder 3:50)
    Busy in legislature. Horses and mules being vulnerable to Yankee theft. Problems with Negroes. Marital attachment of a Negro couple.
  - J.T.H. Woodson, Justice of the Peace, Cumberland County, [Virginia], August 24, 1863., D.S. (Box-folder 3:51)
    "In the event Tho[ma]s L.P. Cocke is not sent into the Army" from Elizabeth R[andolph] Cocke, Robert D. Brown, John Hatcher and Nath[anie]l Walton.
  - Dr. J.L. Woodville to T[homas] L.P. Cocke, 1867-1869., Ms. S. (Box-folder 3:52)
    Bill for horses and corn.
  - Richard P. Jones, Warner T. Taliaferro, Alexander G. Taliaferro, William T. Burwell to Henry H. Harrison, Clark County, December 1868., D. Dr. (Box-folder 3:53)
    Management and/or sale of property in London.
  - Benj[amin] S. Ewell, Williamsburg [Virginia] to Mrs. E[lizabeth] R[andolph] Cocke, Cartersville [Virginia], Sep[tembe]r 16, 1869., ALSC and T. (Box-folder 3:54)
    Letter describing place of Randolphs and Prestons at the College of William and Mary, part of a program for raising the endowment.
  - Geo[rge] C. Lee, Lexington, Virginia to Mr. Tom [Thomas L.P. Cocke], Dec[ember] 23, 1871., ALS. (Box-folder 3:55)
    Mother visiting her son in Washington. Plans for Christmas. [Plus, Ms. note from Mrs. Maria C. Talcott.]
  - M[argaret] J. P[reston, wife of J.T.L. Preston], January 31, 1889., Ms. P. (Box-folder 3:56)
    Obituary taken from the Southern Churchman of Mrs. Elizabeth Randolph Cocke. [Ms. notes by Mrs. Maria C. Talcott].
  - [Southern Churchman], [February] 1889., Cl. (Box-folder 3:57)
    Obituary, Mrs. Harriet Sheldon, wife of Jacob C. Sheldon, daughter of John Dixon.
  - Aunt Maggie [Margaret J. Preston], Lexington, Virginia to Tom [Thomas Lewis Preston Cocke], [18]90., T. (Box-folder 3:58)
    Death of Uncle [J.T.L.] Preston. Family news.
  - Alfred W. Gibbs, Altoona, [Pennsylvania] to Miss [Ganmi?], Aug[ust] 9, 1899., ALS. (Box-folder 3:59)
    A present for Miss Martha.
  - Issue of The Times-Dispatch Richmond, Virginia, January 20, 1907., N. (Box-folder 3:60)
    Devoted to Robert E. Lee.
  - William Ronald Cocke III, [July 2, 1936]., Cl. (Box-folder 3:61)
    Descendants of Gentlemen-Adventurer will celebrate Henrico Grant of 1636.
  - Copy, probably taken from a text of the early history of the Romans, n.d., Ms. (Box-folder 3:62)
  - Copy sheet, [18th century]., Ms. (Box-folder 3:63)
  - J. E. Hall, [19th century]., Cop. (Box-folder 3:64)
    Engraving of letter from G[eorge] Washington, Mount Vernon, to Fran[ci]s Hopkinson, May 16, 1785; "for the Port Folio."
  - Lucy A[nn] Page, Wareham, to [cousin] Mrs. Harriet P. Sheldon, Williamsburg [Virginia], [mid 19th c. March 28]., ALS. (Box-folder 3:65)
    Recent death of her husband [Mann Page.] Visitors Sophia and Lizzie Tompkins.
  - Third Regiment Virginia Calvalry, Roll of Company G., n.d., T. Cop. (Box-folder 3:66)
    Carbon copy of "Third Regiment Virginia Calvalry, Roll of Company G, Cumberland County."
  - Religious poem, n.d., Ms. Fragment. (Box-folder 3:67)
    Religious poem.
  - Charade Valedictory, [19th century]., Ms. (Box-folder 3:68)
  - "Valedictory", a poem, [19th century]., Ms. (Box-folder 3:69)
  - Fragments, undated., Ms. Fragments. (Box-folder 3:70)
  - Cartridge Box, October 27, 1863., MuL. (Box-folder 4:1)
    Made by C.S. Laboratory, Richmond, [Virginia].
  - Copy book of poems, n.d., Ms. V. (Box-folder 4:2)
    Copy book of poems.
  - Scrapbook about taxes and tariff, Undated., Cl. V. (Box-folder 4:3)
  Series 5: Jones Family Papers
- Papers of Richard P. Jones and his family of, "Lands End," Gloucester County, Virginia, 1851-1863. (Box-folder 4:4-10)